Southwest Folklore Center Sound Disc Collection, 1945-1987
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Southwest Folklore Center Sound Disc Collection, 1945-1987
SWF 008
University of Arizona. Southwest Folklore Center.
Sound discs of Mexican American, Native American and square dance music, acquired by the Southwest Folklore Center after 1980. Recordings in this collection are in 33-1/3, 45 and 78 rpm formats.
512 sound discs
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
Restricted. Researchers must use cassette tape copies of all sound discs or tape reels when they are available. An item level listing of all sound discs in the collection is available at the end of this document. Tape reel duplicates of the sound discs are numbered to correspond to the call numbers of the sound discs themselves.
Historical Note
Since its creation in 1979, the Southwest Folklore Center has served as an archive for folk material. Its activities include actively researching and collecting information about Arizona's folk communities, generating outreach programs, and coordinating folk activities throughout the state. The compact disks located in the Archives have been collected since the early 1990s, and are mostly commercial recordings of various musicians, poets, and musical groups from Mexico and the southwestern United States. Collection activity is ongoing.
Arrangement
Arranged according to accession into the collection.
Scope and Content Note
This collection consists of sound discs acquired by the Center since 1980. The collection emphasizes Mexican American music, Native American music, and square dance music. Sound discs containing similar material but acquired before 1980 may be found in the Southwest Folklore Center Pre-1980 Sound Disc Collection, with call number SWF 007.
Access Terms
Accordion music
Corridos
Cowboys - Songs and music
Folk music – Arizona
Folk songs, Spanish
Indians of Mexico – Music
Indians of North America - Arizona – Music
Indians of North America – Southwest
Mariachi music
Mexican Americans – Music
Organ music
Polkas
Apache Indians – Music
Blackfeet Indians – Music
Hopi Indians – Music
Navajo Indians – Music
Pima Indians – Music
Tohono O'odham Indians – Music
Waila (Chicken scratch music)
Revolutionary ballads and songs – Mexico
Container List
- Caissons, Schmelzer, Dan, 1950; Los Angeles, CA., New Old Timer Records, c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Dance written and called by Dan Schmelzer... Singing square dance with calls and singing square dance instrumental.; SWF 1980.1/D(45) OT.201 (7in.)
- Glad rag doll, Earle Park, 1950; Los Angeles, CA., New Old Timer Records, c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Dance written and called by Earle Park... Singing square dance with calls and singing square dance instrumental... Glad rag doll --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) OT.203 (7in.)
- In the arms of love, Schmelzer, Dan, 1950; Los Angeles, CA., New Old Timer Records, c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Dance written and called by Dan Schmelzer... Singing square dance with calls and singing square dance instrumental... In the arms of love --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) OT.204 (7in.)
- Little brown gal, McCullar, Mac, 1950; Los Angeles, CA., New Old Timer Records, c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Dance by Mac McCullar... Singing square dance with calls and singing square dance instrumental... Little brown gal --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) OT.205 (7in.)
- Say howdy, McMullar, Mac, 1950; Los Angeles, CA., New Old Timer Records, c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Dance written and called by Mac McMullar... Singing square dance with calls and singing square dance instrumental... Say howdy --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) OT.207 (7in.)
- Lonesome, Jones, Art and Dave Roe, 1950; Los Angeles, CA., New Old Timer Records, c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Art Jones... Called by Dave Roe... Square dance with calls and square dance music only... Lonesome --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) OT.1001 (7in.)
- Travelin' on, Square Notes and Smokey Snook, 1950; Phoenix AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Square Notes... Called by Smokey Snook... Square dance with calls and square dance with music only... Travelin' on --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) OT.1102 (7in.)
- Pistol packin' mama, Arkansas Mountain Boys, 1950; Phoenix AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Arkansas Mountain Boys... Smokey Snook, caller... Square dance with calls and square dance music only... Pistol packin' mama --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) OT.1103 (7in.)
- It's hard to be humble, Schroeder's Playboys, 1950; Phoenix AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Schroeder's Playboys... Lee Hailey, caller... Square dance with calls and square dance with music only... It's hard to be humble --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) OT.1201 (7in.)
- Tequila Sheila, Schroeder's Playboys, 1950; Phoenix AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Schroeder's Playboys... Lee Hailey, caller... Square dance with calls and square dance music only... Tequila Sheila --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) OT.1202 (7in.)
- Bye bye blackbird, The Four Squares, Phoenix AZ., Old Timer Record Co.; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by The Four Squares... Called by Larry Ingber... Square dance with calls and square dance music only... Bye bye blackbird --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) OT.1301 (7in.)
- Somebody's been beatin' my time, The Rangers, 1950; Phoenix AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by the Rangers... Dick Kenyon, caller... Square dance with calls and square dance music only... Somebody's been beatin' my time --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) OT.1501 (7in.)
- Love's sweeter the second time around, Jones, Art, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Art Jones... Called by Dick Kenyon... Square dance with calls and square dance music only... Love's sweeter the second time around --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) OT.1502 (7in.)
- Kitten kapers, Jones, Art, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., p1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Art Jones... Cued by Glenn and Rosie King... Square dance with cues and square dance without cues... Kitten kapers; SWF 1980.1/D(45) OT.1901 (7in.)
- Two man theme -- Pinetop boogie, The Gruesome Twosome, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc (6 min.), analog, 78 rpm, 10 in.; Performed by The Gruesome Twosome... Two man theme -- Pinetop boogie --; SWF 1980.1/D(78) OT.7001 (10in.)
- Melody of love -- That naughty waltz, Jerry Jacka Trio, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc (6 min.), analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Performed by Jerry Jacka Trio... Melody of love -- That naughty waltz --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) S.7004 (7in.)
- Travelin on, Ables Square Notes, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Ables Square Notes... Keith Able, caller... Square dance with calls and square dance without calls... Travelin' on --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) 7005 (7in.)
- Varsoviana -- Red River Valley, Ramsey, Clay and the Old Timers, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Performed by Clay Ramsey and the Old Timers... Square dance with calls... Varsoviana -- Red River Valley --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) 8001 (7in.)
- Western schottish -- Golden slippers, Ramsey, Clay and the Old Timers, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Clay Ramsey and the Old Timers... Square dance without calls... Western schottish -- Golden slippers --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) 8002 (7in.)
- Chicago glide -- Virginia reel, Ramsey, Clay and the Old Timers, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Performed by Clay Ramsey and the Old Timers... Chicago glide -- Virginia Reel/Irish washerwoman --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) 8006 (7in.)
- Rye waltz -- Home sweet home, Ramsey, Clay and the Old Timers, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Performed by Clay Ramsey and the Old Timers... Rye waltz -- Home sweet home/Goodnight waltz --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) 8009 (7in.)
- Halfway -- Saturday night breakdown, Sexton, Roy and his Arizona Hoedowners, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Roy Sexton and his Arizona Hoedowners... Roy Sexton, fiddle; Bill Harris, guitar; and Clyde Armentrout, bass... Square dance without calls... Halfway -- Saturday night breakdown --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) 8010 (7in.)
- Nobody's business -- Bully of the town, Sexton, Roy and his Arizona Hoedowners, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Roy Sexton and his Arizona Hoedowners... Roy Sexton, fiddle; Bill Harris, guitar; and Clyde Armentrout, bass... Square dance without calls... Nobody's business -- Bully of the town --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) 8013 (7in.)
- Double the dose -- Spinning wheel, Sexton, Roy and his Arizona Hoedowners, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Roy Sexton and his Arizona Hoedowners... Johnny Milton, caller... Square dance with calls... Double the dose/Chinese breakdown -- Spinning wheel/Liberty --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) 8016 (7in.)
- Four gents star, or Sutters Mill -- Cowboy loop, Sexton, Roy and his Arizona Hoedowners, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Roy Sexton and his Arizona Hoedowners... Johnny Milton, caller... Square dance with calls... Four gents star, or Sutters Mill/Whistling Rufus -- Cowboy loop/Gal I left behind me --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) 8017 (7in.)
- Half sashay -- Sides divide, Delk, Fiddlin' Forrest and his Gully Jumpers, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Fiddlin' Forrest Delk and his Gully Jumpers... Butch Nelson, caller... Square dance with calls... Half sashay/Sally Goodin -- Sides divide/Soldiers joy --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) 8024 (7in.)
- Under the double eagle -- Mormon Schottiche, Delk, Fiddlin' Forrest and his Gully Jumpers, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Fiddlin' Forrest Delk and his Gully Jumpers... Under the double eagle/Grand march -- Mormon Schottiche/Twinkle, twinkle, little star --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) 8026 (7in.)
- Great big taters in sandy land -- Turkey in the straw, Delk, Fiddlin' Forrest and his Gully Jumpers, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Fiddlin' Forrest and his Gully Jumpers... Square dance without calls... Great big taters in sandy land -- Turkey in the straw --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) 8027 (7in.)
- Draggin' the bow -- Wednesday night waltz, Delk, Fiddlin' Forrest and his Gully Jumpers, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc (6 min.), analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Fiddlin' Forrest Delk and his Gully Jumpers... Draggin' the bow -- Wednesday night waltz --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) S.8029 (7in.)
- Hell amongst the yearlings -- Eighth of January, Ramsey, Clay and the Old Timers, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc (8 min.), analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Clay Ramsey and the Old Timers... Square dance without calls... Hell amongst the yearlings -- Eighth of January --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) 8032 (7in.)
- Tennessee wagonner -- Buffalo gals, Ramsey, Clay and the Old Timers, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc (8 min.), analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Clay Ramsey and the Old Timers... Square dance without calls... Tennessee wagonner -- Buffalo gals --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) 8033 (7in.)
- Chinese breakdown -- Leather britches, Ramsey, Clay and the Old Timers, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc (8 min.), analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Clay Ramsey and the Old Timers... Square dance without calls... Chinese breakdown -- Leather britches --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) 8034 (7in.)
- Crawdads -- Red River Valley, Ramsey, Clay and the Old Timers, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc (8 min.), analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Clay Ramsey and the Old Timers... Bob Merkley, caller... Singing square dance with calls as originated by Bob Merkley... Crawdads -- Red River Valley --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) 8037 (7in.)
- Hinky dink parley voo -- Let's have a barrel of fun, Ramsey, Clay and the Old Timers, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc (6 min.), analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Clay Ramsey and the Old Timers... Milton Paisant, caller... Singing square dance with calls as originated by Milton Paisant... Hinky dink parley voo -- Let's have a barrel of fun --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) 8038 (7in.)
- I'll swing yours, you swing mine -- Elbow swing, Ramsey, Clay and the Old Timers, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc (8 min.), analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Clay Ramsey and the Old Timers... Cal Golden, caller... Square dance with calls... I'll swing yours, you swing mine/Ragtime Annie) -- Elbow swing/Mississippi Sawyer) --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) 8039 (7in.)
- Arkansas star -- Sioux City Sioux, Ramsey, Clay and the Old Timers, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Clay Ramsey and the Old Timers... Cal Golden, caller... Square dance with calls... Arkansas star -- Sioux City Sioux --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) S.8040 (7in.)
- Virginia reel -- Brown eyed Mary, Clay and the Old Timers, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Clay Ramsey and the Old Timers... Mrs. Johnny Melton, caller... Two complete changes... Virginia reel -- Brown eyed Mary --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) S.8051 (7in.)
- Sweet Georgia Brown -- When you wore a tulip, Cal Golden's Arkansas Mountain Boys, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc (8 min.), analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Cal Golden's Arkansas Mountain Boys... Harry Raby, pianist... Square dance without calls... Sweet Georgia Brown -- When you wore a tulip --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) S.8054 (7in.)
- Pistol packin' mama -- Spanish cavalero, Cal Golden's Arkansas Mountain Boys, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Cal Golden's Arkansas Mountain Boys... Harry Raby, pianist... Square dance without calls... Pistol packin' mama -- Spanish cavalero --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) S.8055 (7in.)
- Rocky mountain goat -- Gray eagle, Cal Golden's Arkansas Mountain Boys, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc (9 min.), analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Cal Golden's Arkansas Mountain Boys... Jack Carter, fiddler... Square dance without calls... Rocky mountain goat -- Gray eagle --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) S.8057 (7in.)
- Oklahoma cyclone -- Chain lightening, Delk, Fiddlin' Forrest and his Gully Jumpers, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc (7 min.), analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Fiddlin' Forrest Delk and his Gully Jumpers... Butch Nelson, caller... Square dance with calls... Oklahoma cyclone -- Chain lightening --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) S.8061 (7in.)
- Barnacle Bill square, The Arkansas Mountain Boys, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by the Arkansas Mountain Boys... Cal Golden, caller... Singing square dance without calls... Barnacle Bill square --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) S.8067 (7in.)
- Calcasieu Jambalaya -- Shift the gears, Johnny Balmer's Grand Canyon Boys, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Johnny Balmer's Grand Canyon Boys... Bill Castner, caller... Square dance with calls... Calcasieu Jambalaya -- Shift the gears --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) S.8068 (7in.)
- Texas plains, Cal Golden's Arkansas Mountain Boys, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Cal Golden's Arkansas Mountain Boys... Cal Golden, caller... Singing square dance with calls and singing square dance without calls... Texas plains --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) S.8069 (7in.)
- Little brown jug -- Put your little foot, Delk, Fiddlin' Forrest and his Gully Jumpers, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc (6 min.), analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Fiddlin' Forrest Delk and his Gully Jumpers... Little brown jug -- Put your little foot --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) S.8071 (7in.)
- Wearing of the green, Johnny Balmer's Grand Canyon Boys, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Johnny Balmer's Grand Canyon Boys... Bill Castner, caller... Singing square dance with calls and singing square dance without calls... Wearing of the green --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) S.8077 (7in.)
- Puddy Tat square -- Whirlpool square, Johnny Balmer's Grand Canyon Boys, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc (8 min.), analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Johnny Balmer's Grand Canyon Boys... Johnny Schultz, caller... Singing square dance with calls and singing square dance without calls... Puddy Tat square/Cripple Creek -- Whirlpool square/Whirlpool hoedown --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) S.8080 (7in.)
- Don't look back -- Apache square, Ramsey, Clay and the Old Timers, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc (8 min.), analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Clay Ramsey and the Old Timers... Jim Brooks, caller... Square dance with calls... Don't look back/Chinese breakdown -- Apache square/Flop Eared Mule --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) S.8083 (7in.)
- Cindy -- Tulip square, Cal Golden's Arkansas Mountain Boys, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc (7 min.), analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Cal Golden's Arkansas Mountain Boys... Jim Brooks, caller... Singing square dance with calls... Cindy -- Tulip square --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) S.8084 (7in.)
- Hometown square, Johnny Balmer's Grand Canyon Boys, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc (6 min.), analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Johnny Balmer's Grand Canyon Boys... Johnny Schultz, caller... Singing square dance with calls... Hometown square/Dear hearts and gentle people --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) S.8085 (7in.)
- Hokey pokey, Johnny Balmer's Grand Canyon Boys, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc (5 min.), analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Johnny Balmer's Grand Canyon Boys... Bill Castner, caller... Square dance with calls and square dance without calls... Hokey pokey --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) S.8086 (7in.)
- Jolly is the miller, Johnny Balmer's Grand Canyon Boys, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc (7 min.), analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Johnny Balmer's Grand Canyon Boys... Bill Castner, caller... Mixer with calls and mixer without calls... Jolly is the miller --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) S.8089 (7in.)
- Open up your heart -- 12th Street rag, Jerry Jacka Trio, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Jerry Jacka Trio... Johnny Schultz, caller... Singing square dance with calls... Open up your heart -- 12th Street rag --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) S.8095 (7in.)
- This ole house, Jerry Jacka Trio, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Jerry Jacka Trio... Johnny Schultz, caller... Singing square dance with calls and singing square dance without calls... This ole house --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) S.8099 (7in.)
- Chiapanecas -- La Raspa, Jerry Jacka Trio, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 2 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Jerry Jacka Trio... Mexican folk dance...Chiapanecas -- La Raspa; SWF 1980.1/D(45) 8100
- Heart of my heart -- Poor little robin, Johnny Balmer's Grand Canyon Boys, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Johnny Balmer's Grand Canyon Boys... Morris Sevada, caller... Singing square dance with calls... Heart of my heart -- Poor little robin --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) S.8102 (7in.)
- Heart of my heart -- Poor little robin, Johnny Balmer's Grand Canyon Boys, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Johnny Balmer's Grand Canyon Boys... Morris Sevada, caller... Singing square dance with calls... Heart of my heart -- Poor little robin --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) S.8103 (7in.)
- Mister Sandman, Jerry Jacka Trio, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Jerry Jacka Trio... Johnny Schultz, caller... Singing square dance with calls and singing square dance without calls... Mister Sandman --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) S.8104 (7in.)
- Split your corners hash -- Blue Island blister, Johnny Balmer's Grand Canyon Boys, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Johnny Balmer's Grand Canyon Boys... Roy Sutton, caller... Square dance with calls... Split your corners hash (Music: Tom and Jerry) -- Blue Island blister (Music: Fireball special) --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) S.8105 (7in.)
- The Route -- Oak Lawn merrygoround, Johnny Balmer's Grand Canyon Boys, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Johnny Balmer's Grand Canyon Boys... "Uncle Walt" Wentworth, caller... Square dance with calls... The Route (Music: Fireball special) -- Oak Lawn merrygoround (Music: Tom and Jerry) --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) S.8106 (7in.)
- Walkabout -- Joyride, Jerry Jacka Trio, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by Jerry Jacka Trio... Walkabout (Music: Walkin' along - Round dance) -- Joyride (Round dance) --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) S.8107 (7in.)
- Teasin', The Cottonpickin' Five, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by the Cottonpickin' Five... Butch Nelson, caller... Chuck Moon, fiddle; Johnny Balmer, banjo; Jerry Jacka, accordion; Bill Harris, guitar; Everett Helman, bass... Singing square dance with calls and singing square dance without calls... Teasin' --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) S.8109 (7in.)
- Sailing down that old Green River, The Cottonpickin' Five, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by the Cottonpickin' Five... Butch Nelson, caller... Chuck Moon, fiddle; Johnny Balmer, banjo; Jerry Jacka, accordion; Bill Harris, guitar; Everett Helman, bass... Singing square dance with calls and singing square dance without calls... Sailing down that old Green River --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) S.8110 (7in.)
- Hoop dee doo, The Cottonpickin' Five, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by the Cottonpickin' Five... Butch Nelson, caller... Chuck Moon, fiddle; Johnny Balmer, banjo; Jerry Jacka, accordion; Bill Harris, guitar; Everett Helman, bass... Singing square dance with calls and singing square dance without calls... Hoop dee doo --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) S.8111 (7in.)
- Raggin' the call, The Cottonpickin' Five, 1950; Phoenix, AZ., Old Timer Record Co., c1950; 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Music by the Cottonpickin' Five... Butch Nelson, caller... Chuck Moon, fiddle; Johnny Balmer, banjo; Jerry Jacka, accordion; Bill Harris, guitar; Everett Helman, bass... Singing square dance with calls and singing square dance without calls... Raggin' the call --; SWF 1980.1/D(45) S.8112 (7in.)